## **(**647) 679-8032

# Alireza Torabian

☑ torabian@yorku.ca

torabian.alireza@gmail.com Graduate Student / Experienced in Machine Learning

Computer science graduate student at York University researching in the field of machine learning calibration with a strong background in mathematics. Experienced in developing machine learning models and the theory behind them. Have done several projects in various areas, especially deep learning, adversarial machine learning, and NLP, mostly using Tensorflow and Keras.

#### **EDUCATION**

York University 2021-2022 (Expected)

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Advised by Ruth Urner, GPA: A+

Toronto, Canada

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)

2015-2020

B.Sc. in Computer (Software) Engineering, Advised by Saeedeh Momtazi, *GPA:* 3.9/4 (18.25/20) (In the top 10%)

Tehran, Iran

Thesis: Design and Implementation of a Persian Automatic Question Answering System

#### **EXPERIENCE**

York University Jan. 2021 – Present

Research Assistant, Machine Learning

Toronto, Canada

• Explored desirable properties of calibration models as well as evaluation metrics and analyzed their feasibility and correspondences.

# National University of Singapore, Data Privacy and Trustworthy Machine Learning Research Lab

Jul. 2019 - Sep. 2019

Research Intern, Adversarial Machine Learning

. Singapore

- Created a black-box adversarial attack to fool face recognition models for enhancing face privacy on social media achieved 35% success rate.
- To fool face detection models, the attack model is optimized to minimize the intersection of the detected face and the original face.
- The face recognition attack model maximizes the similarity of the recognized face's latent feature and a target face.

**Diaalog**Research and Development Intern, NLP

Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Developed a Persian question answering system to generate answers according to the input questions in Python Tensorflow.

• Using a sequence-to-sequence model and clustering methods.

## Amirkabir University of Technology, Cognitive Robotics Lab

Oct. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Research Assistant

Tehran, Iran

Tehran, Iran

Developed an autonomous exploration algorithm for robots to help them explore a map simultaneously from different starting points in C++.

### **SKILLS**

Languages Python, Java, C++, Go

Frameworks and Tools TensorFlow (Python & JS), Keras, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn

Databases MySQL, SPARQL, MongoDB

Web Design JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Express.js, PHP

Other Tools Git, Unix shell, Jupyter

#### **PROJECTS**

## Alternative Actor and Co-Star Suggestion Using a Graph Autoencoder Model

Apr. 2021

- Applied a graph autoencoder to a network of actors using Keras in Python achieved 99.46% accuracy on reconstruction the graph.
- An alternative actor is found by searching the latent space using a K-d tree.
- A co-star is suggested according to the predicted weights from an autoencoder model.

#### **Persian Question Answering System**

Aug. 2020

- Developed a question answering system using a knowledge-base in Python.
- SVM and CNN classification models used to classify questions achieved 96% accuracy and F1-score of 92.7%.

## **Optimization Coursework**

Jul. 2019

• Implemented unconstrained and constrained optimizations, such as line search, trust region, and log barrier for convex problems.

## **Neural Dialogue System**

Dec. 2018

• Implemented a Seq2Seq model with an attention mechanism, using **Tensorflow** in **Python**.

## **HONORS AND AWARDS**

York University Fellowship, C\$62,500 for my master's studies	2021-2022
Second Place in the rescue simulation virtual robot league at RoboCup in Nagoya, Japan	2017
Ranked top 0.5% in nationwide Iranian university entrance exam among 180,000 participants	2015
Member of National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents (NODET)	2011-2015